They put me in the actual prison with
the pedophiles and the mafia dons and
the drug kingpins. What should I do? And
he said, "Oh my god." He says, "Well, we
can file a motion, but it'll be 2 years
before we get a court date and you'll be
home by then." He said, "Buddy, I'm
sorry. You're just going to have to
tough it out."
>> This is Virtuous Leaders, the podcast
for based Catholics who will speak
truth, do good, or die trying. Here's
the show.
[Music]
So, you were a former CIA agent who was
persecuted by our own government for
telling the truth. You knew you were
facing forces both powerful and corrupt.
Why did you choose to do the right
thing?
>> Well, I um I wish I could tell you that
it was solely for altruistic purposes
and it wasn't in the beginning. It w it
became so later because I doubled down.
But in the beginning,
this torture program was so egregiously
wrong. It was so obviously
unethical, immoral, illegal that I
thought certainly somebody's going to
come out and say something right.
Somebody's going to come out and blow
the whistle. And nobody did. And I kept
waiting for somebody to do it and nobody
did. And then finally in December of
2007, Brian Ross from ABC News called me
and said that he had a source who said
that I had tortured Abu Zubeda. I said
that was absolutely untrue. I was the
only person who was kind to Abu Zuba and
in fact I've never laid a hand on any
prisoner ever. And he said, "Well,
you're welcome to come on the show and
defend yourself." And so I decided in
the week between that call and actually
going on ABC News that I would simply
tell the truth. and he whatever he asked
of me, I was going to tell the truth.
Well, as soon as the as soon as I I gave
that interview and as I always say, the
weight of the entire US government fell
on my head, I um I doubled down and the
deeper I got into it, the more I was
convinced I was right and they were
wrong, that history was going to judge
us, and that I was going to stick by my
guns. And that's what I did. And now
here we are all these years later and I
was right.
I'm glad I did it.
>> Wow, you were right.
So this is this is what I want to focus
on. You had an excellent interview with
Tucker Carlson and the details of the
story. I want to get into
the the inner life of that decision and
working through that decision
because I think increasingly we're in a
situation where we are going to be asked
to make sacrifices to speak the truth
and do and do the good.
>> So first thing you had a week up to that
ABC interview in which you decided I I
will speak the truth.
>> What was going through your head during
that week? you I presume you're weighing
the pros and cons and the suffering that
would result.
>> Yeah. I never I never wanted to go
public. It was something that was forced
on me. And I thought
I thought, you know, generations are
going to look back on this. Generations
of my own family,
uh children that had not yet been born
to me. Uh grandchildren I've, you know,
not yet met.
And I want them to be able to say to
their children and grandchildren that I
had done the right thing. And I thought
if they're going to out me like this, if
they're going to make this a public
spectacle, then I'm going to be on the
right side of it.
And you know, at first at first it was
it was difficult in that just the
statement that the CIA was torturing
prisoners was so controversial and so
polarizing that even before I I
encountered any legal trouble, friends
and even family members began walking
away from me.
And so you really get to see who your
true friends are, who your real
supporters are.
And then
when charges were filed against me when
was it 3 years later
that really puts things into
perspective.
And so, you know, as as odd as it might
sound, it was almost a culling exercise
where I was able to dispatch fake
people, phonies, from my life and focus
on the people who really loved and
supported me. On top of that, I'm going
to be careful with my language here
because of the wording of my divorce
decree.
You know, there are some people
committed to the long run. There are
some people who take the words for
better or for worse seriously. And
though there are others who do not.
And so as difficult
of an experience as this became,
I feel like I'm a better and stronger
person because of it.
>> Wow. I was not expecting that. Thank you
for sharing that. And I I appreciate
actually hearing that because
I I was disappointed when I heard that
that divorce happened. And but I'm happy
to hear that at least reading between
the lines, you had the desire to be
faithful.
>> Oh boy, did I. Yeah. Uh you I My parents
were married for let's see 42 years when
my dad passed away and my parents were
deeply in love with each other.
I just I grew up assuming that everybody
was like that.
>> You know,
when when life throws you a curve, you
band together and you deal with it.
I thought
not everybody's like that. Some head for
the hills and go into self-preservation
mode at the expense of of everyone and
everything else.
So, you suffered a lot internally and
externally.
>> It's been bad. Yeah, it's been bad. On
top of the fact that the that the Obama
Justice Department seized my federal
pension after 20 years of service. So,
I'm going to have to work until the day
I die unless Donald Trump elects to give
me a pardon. Yeah.
>> Why hasn't he?
>> I don't know. I don't know. I feel like
I'm that close and I'm in touch with
very important people who uh are in
Trump's immediate orbit. So, I'm I'm
hoping that this is just a question of
timing. Uh I don't know. We'll see. I
don't know.
>> Okay. I Man, I I really hope he has
something captured.
>> Yeah. Me, too.
Me, too. We'll see.
>> Yeah. Um, just out of respect for the
delicacy of your situation, I I won't
ask you to comment too much on that.
>> Thank you. I appreciate that.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, I'm very curious. So,
you did spend a couple years in prison.
>> What was that like?
>> Yeah, it was surreal. I spent 23 months
in a federal prison, an actual prison.
You know, when I was being sentenced, my
attorney stood up and said, um,
well, they they didn't say they asked
the judge to send me to a minimum
security work camp. And in a minimum
security camp, the camps are always
attached to a higher security prison
because in the event of a riot or a
lockdown, it's the people at the camp
that do the laundry and do the cooking
and do the mopping and the sweeping and
stuff like that.
So
the prosecutors had no objection and the
judge then ordered that I be sent to a
minimum security work camp. Now there
are no bars on the windows. The doors
are unlocked. Most of the the inmates
work in town at the local university.
You're just on your honor not to run
away.
>> That that's the gig that Epstein got.
>> No, he got even better. He got house
arrest.
>> Oh, okay.
>> In his own in his own home.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. So, this is what Gain Maxwell has
right now. She's got minimum security.
Even though she's a convicted child sex
predator and they're not permitted in
minimum security camps, she's in a
minimum security camp. So, figure that
out. Anyway, I go to the camp. What you
do, it's very odd. This is why I use the
word surreal. You just drive up to the
prison and knock on the door and say
you're there to turn yourself in.
>> It's It's weird. So, I mean, unless it's
a violent crime, in which case they cuff
you in the courtroom and then just take
you. Um, you're just, you know, they
send you a letter and they say, "On this
date, at this time, turn yourself in."
So, I drove up there with a couple of my
attorneys, a documentary film crew, my
cousin and his son knock on the door,
they say, "You have to go across the
street to the prison. They'll process
you and then they'll walk you back over
here." I said, "Okay, fine." So, I go
across the street to the prison. They
put me through security and then they
start taking me around to the back of
the actual prison. I said, "No, no, I'm
supposed to be at the camp across the
street." And the guard laughed at me and
he said, "Not according to my paperwork.
You're not."
>> Oh my gosh.
>> And I told myself, "Take it easy.
There's nothing you can do. If you raise
a stink, they're going to put you in
solitary." So, I didn't say a word.
Well, it took me 4 days to get access to
a phone. And I called my lead attorney
and I said, "Hey, they put me in the
actual prison with the pedophiles and
the mafia dons and the drug kingpins.
What should I do?" And he said, "Oh my
god." He says, "Well, we can file a
motion, but it'll be 2 years before we
get a court date and you'll be home by
then." He said, "Buddy, I'm sorry.
You're just going to have to tough it
out."
>> Oh my gosh. What?
>> And so I decided, you know what? I'm
trained for this. I've lived in far
worse places than a low security prison
in Lorettto, Pennsylvania. So, I just
decided to rely on my on my CIA training
to keep myself safe and at the top of
the social heap. That's what I did. It
was hard work, but it worked out.
>> That's fascinating. What did you do to
to achieve those goals? I wrote a book
while I was in prison called Doing Time
Like a Spy: How the CIA Taught Me to
Survive and Thrive in Prison. And I take
these 20 lessons that they taught us in
CIA training, and I showed how I applied
each and every one of these lessons to
prison life. I mean, some of them, even
in CIA training, we used to say them as
a joke, like admit nothing, deny
everything, make counter accusations.
That was kind of a joke, but it was a
real thing in prison. Lessons like, "Let
others do your dirty work. Never draw
attention to yourself. Seek and utilize
available cover." And it worked. It
worked. Do you remember, you you might
be a little bit too young, but there was
an HBO show that started in 2000 called
Oz. And it was a a show about prison,
about this maximum security penitentiary
in I think it was Illinois. And they had
a a unit in it called Oz where they
brought together three mob guys, three
Nazis, three black nationalists, you
know, all these different gangs and sort
of forced them to get along with each
other. And of course they didn't. It was
just chaos and murder and mayhem. But
there was one character in there who was
Irish and he was independent. He wasn't
in any gang. That was me. I had to play
them one off the other and make sure
that I never got wrapped up in the
fighting and the bickering and the
shanks and the, you know, all that
craziness that they were constantly
plotting against each other. In the end,
I was allied with the Italians. They
adopted me, but I was mostly independent
and just looked out for myself.
>> What was the scariest situation you were
in?
There was a serial killer in my unit, a
guy that was a long-distance truck
driver. And so his nickname was truck.
And he had this bad habit of picking up
prostitutes at truck stops and having
sex with them and then strangling them
because he didn't want to pay. And one
of the girls that he strangled was 16
and she actually lived and she was able
to identify him. So he ended up with two
consecutive 20-year terms. So, I met him
when he was about 35 years into this
40-year sentence for reasons that were
never clear to me. He constantly sought
my approval. Constantly. He started off
by saying that he had been in the CIA.
And I was like, "Dude, you don't even
have teeth and you can't see." I didn't
know what he was in for. So, I was very
disrespectful to him. And people would
come up to me and say, "Hey, listen.
He's a dangerous so, you should back
off. The Italians told me that. So, I
stopped insulting him. And then he would
do things like, "Hey, John, I saved you
a seat in the TV room to watch the
football game." I said, "Oh, thanks,
Truck. Hey, John. I know you listen to
classic rock. There's a new station at
1600 a.m. Oh, thanks, Truck. Appreciate
it." He hated pedophiles more than
anything, and it was because he was a
pedophile. So, while this is taking
place, there's an opening in my cell,
right? One of the guys got transferred
out. And when there's an opening in your
cell, all the cellmates get together and
you interview people who want to move
into your cell. So, rule number one, no
pedophiles. None. Rule number two, no
rats. So, if you're not a rat and you're
not a pedophile, I want to make sure
that you're you're clean, you keep your
space clean, you don't smell bad, you're
not an [__] and then, you know,
maybe we'll let you into our cell. And
then we all go to
>> they were fourman cells, but they
stuffed six of us in there. So, six
people in a fourman cell. So, this guy
from Pittsburgh says he wants to move
into our cell. And we used to call him
Cat in the Hat because he had a really
oblong head. It was like freakish. And I
said, "What's your crime? You're not a
pedophile, right?" And he said, "No, I'm
not a pedophile." I said, "What's your
crime?" He says, "Murder for hire." And
I said, "Ooh, I'm not sure I like that
either. What were the circumstances of
that?" And he said, "Oh, I hired a
hitman." He said, "I owed the mafia
$100,000 in gambling debts, so I took
out a life insurance policy on my
business partner, and I hired a hitman
to kill him, and I got caught." I said,
"That's that's not cool." So, I went
down to the law library and I looked him
up and the case was much more
complicated than that. Like, all of that
was true. He hired the hitman and then
he got caught within days of the murder
cuz who else? You just took a $100,000
life insurance policy out on your
partner and boom, like magic, he gets
assassinated. So, of course, they're
going to arrest you. He immediately
ratted out the hitman and he saved
himself. So instead of life without
parole or the federal death penalty, he
got 20 years. And then it just so
happened that the hitman had a heart
attack while awaiting trial and died. So
the feds had to respect the deal that
they made with Cat in the Hat. So I told
Cat in the Hat, "You're a rat. I have
documentary proof you're a rat and
you're not moving into my cell." Okay.
Couple days later, I get called to the
lieutenant's office. Normally, you never
ever want to get called to the
lieutenant's office cuz you're probably
going to solitary. But I got called
because NPR wanted to interview me and I
had to sign a release. So, I go down
there, I sign the release, I go back up
to the TV room, and I'm sitting next to
truck and Cat in the Hat is sitting
three feet away from me and he didn't
see that I was sitting by him. And he
turned to the guy next to him and he
says, "Did you hear Kuryaku got called
down to the lieutenant's office?" He
goes, "That guy's a [__] rat. He went
down there to rat us out." I didn't
react at all. And Truck said, "Did you
just hear that guy?" He said, "You're a
[__] rat." And I said, "An hour ago,
I heard him say that you were a
pedophile." Which was totally untrue.
But remember the rule, let others do
your dirty work. Don't attract attention
to yourself. Without saying a word,
truck got up, walked the three feet over
there, and beat him to within an inch of
his life. Cat in the Hat spent 6 weeks
in the hospital. Truck got five more
years added to his term and was upgraded
to a medium security prison. And then
when Cat in the Hat got back, people had
told him what happened. He came to me to
apologize and I said, "Listen, I'm going
to say one final thing to you. If I ever
hear my name cross your lips ever again,
you're dead. Do you understand?" And he
said, "Yes, I understand." That could
have gone bad for me in a couple of
different ways, but I was able to
manipulate this guy to zero out my
problems, and nobody was ever able to
point the finger at me. That's what the
CIA taught me to do.
>> Well, that's really dark.
>> It's an ugly place.
I didn't mean to make you speechless.
>> I don't want to go to prison, that's for
sure.
>> No, it's not good. There's no such thing
as clubfed. I hate when I hear that
term. Prison is prison. There's no such
thing as clubfed. Yeah, you're not going
to play golf or tennis or do gardening.
You're in [__] prison where they
humiliate you, they emasculate you, and
they make you count the days until you
can get out. And even then, you're not
really free. So, yeah, it's not it's not
good.
>> What do you mean even then you're not
really free?
>> Well, then you've got 3 years, 5 years,
10 years of of probation. Pedophiles
have a lifetime of probation. You're not
free to travel. you're not free to
really do anything without asking a
court, you know, multiple times to allow
you to go out there and make a living.
It's awful. You know, I'm trying to make
a living when I get out and I get
invited, for example, to give a speech
in Berlin and I'm going to make five
grand or 10 grand or whatever it was and
the judge is like, "Nope, no travel."
Like, why you you're telling me that I
have to go to Safeway and get a job as a
as a, you know, a shelf stalker for $8
an hour, but I can make 10 grand giving
one speech in Berlin. And you say, "No,
just because I'm a bad guy and I need to
be punished." Either you want me to make
a living or you don't want me to make a
living. And by the way, I have five
children. And then they're like, "Okay,
okay." But then you have to turn your
passport in as soon as you get back.
Like, okay, why? And that was a constant
fight. Constant.
>> You did your time.
>> Oh, yeah. They don't care. They don't
care. I'll tell you another story. I
just told this yesterday on on my own
podcast. When I got out of prison,
listen, I take I take civil liberties
very very seriously. So, when I got out
of prison, I immediately applied to have
my voting rights reinstated.
So, it's not a sexy process. You just go
to the website of the Secretary of State
of your state. So, I live in Virginia
and I filled out the form and it said it
takes about 2 weeks to get your voting
rights reinstated. Well, 3 weeks later,
I hadn't heard anything. So, I called
the Secretary of State's toll-free
number. And this guy answers, "Yeah, may
I help you?" I said, "Yeah, I applied to
have my voting rights restored. It's
been 3 weeks. I haven't heard anything."
"Oh, what's your case number?" So, I
gave him my case number and he goes,
"Oh, oh, like he recognizes me, right?"
He said, "Listen, it's in process. No
problems. it's going to take about
another week. And I said, "Oh, okay.
Thank you. I'm up the phone." A week
later, 7:00 in the morning, my doorbell
rings and I'm up getting the kids ready
for school. So, I go to the door and
it's a courier and he's got this big 11
by14
cardboard envelope and he hands it to
me. It's from the Secretary of State's
office. I pull out this paper and it's a
big pardon decree where the governor of
Virginia has pardoned me. I hadn't
applied for a pardon, but apparently he
followed my case and thought I got
screwed.
>> So, he just took it upon himself to
pardon me, which was the loveliest
>> gesture. I wish Terry McAuliffe would
run run for president. I would vote for
him just for that kindness. So, I get
this big certificate with the gold seal
and the governor's signature. So, he
reinstates my voting rights and
reinstates my state gun rights. Now, I
don't have my federal gun rights back,
so it it was just a a nice gesture. So,
I go down to the courthouse and it was a
Friday and it's the last day to register
to vote. So, I go to fill out the form.
It says, "Have you ever been convicted
of a felony?" And I said, "Yes." "Have
you had your voting rights reinstated?"
"Yes." And this woman calls me around to
the side very discreetly and she says,
"I notice you checked the two boxes."
And I said, "Yeah." And she said, 'The
man who handles cases like yours, he's
on vacation today. And I said, 'Oh no. I
said, today's the last day to register
and I want to vote on Tuesday. And she
said, don't worry about it. We'll take
care of it. And so on Monday, the day
before the election, my doorbell rings
again and it's the guy from the
courthouse came to my house with a voter
registration card
>> and said, "Congratulations." I said,
"You see, now this is exactly how the
system should be. This, not the way the
feds run it." This was incredible. I'm
so grateful to those people. I mean,
these are kind of like nameless
bureaucrats
and former Governor Terry McAuliff. I'm
forever grateful for them and what they
did. So, I'm curious about what it's
like psychologically to and correct me
if I'm wrong, but plead guilty for a
crime you did not commit. Well, that's
that's a good question actually. And
then in the hearing where I had to
change my plea from not guilty to
guilty, you you stand up in front of the
judge and she says, "Are you here to
change your plea?" And you say, "Yes."
"Are you pleading guilty?" "Yes." "Are
you in fact guilty of the crime with
which you were charged?" And I said,
"No. And she says to my attorney,
"Counselor, you may want to have a word
with your client." And he says, "Loud
enough for the stenographer to hear." He
said, "You have to say you're guilty."
And I said, "But I'm not guilty. I just
want the deal." And he said, "I know,
but you have to say you're guilty." So I
said to the judge, "Sure, I'm guilty. I
did it." She said, "You don't sound too
convincing." I said, "Well, I I did it.
I'm guilty and so I'm pleading guilty."
I mean, what are you going to do? I I
say all the time there there's this the
old joke that you know half of the
people in prison are are innocent. Well,
guess what? I met a lot of people in
prison who are innocent. A lot. But do
you roll the dice? If you're being, for
example, for me, I was offered two
years. I was looking at 45 years. Do you
roll the dice knowing that the
government wins 98.2% of its cases?
>> Wow.
>> You can't. And so, are you guilty?
Guilty. Sure, why not? I'm guilty.
>> Wow, that's terrifying.
>> It's bad. Mhm. It's bad. Yes.
>> Well, this is adding evidence to the
hypothesis that we live in a dystopia.
>> Oh, let me let me add one other thing
just to give you an example. There was a
guy in my housing unit, Pat Winter.
Never in my two years did I ever see
somebody who was more out of place in
prison than Pat Winter. This guy had
nine children. Wow. He was a devout
Catholic. Never missed church, even in
the prison chapel every single Sunday.
And I said to him one day, "Pat, what
are you in here for anyway?" And he
said, "Ason." I said, "Aarson?" I said,
'You really don't seem like a guy who
would go out in the middle of the night
and set set something on fire.' He said,
'Well, I I didn't. I said, 'Well, what
happened? And he said that he married
this rich guy's daughter and they had
nine kids and Pat never went to college.
He was like a mechanic or a body shop
guy, barely making ends meet. But his
father-in-law is supplementing his
income, right? Helping him pay for all
this. His father-in-law never liked him
because he was less than what the
father-in-law wanted for his daughter,
right? So the father-in-law comes to Pat
one day and says, "Listen, I want you to
set fire to this building that I own. I
want to collect the insurance money on
it." And Pat says, "Well, that's
illegal." He said, "I know, but I'm
going to give you X amount of money and
you're going to be able to use it as a
down payment on a house and your kids
need to go to school and whatever." So
Pat just went and set the building on
fire
>> and got caught.
>> Yeah. And I said, "And let me guess, you
didn't rat out your father-in-law." He
said, "Of course not." He said, "I never
opened my mouth. I just took it and I
got five years." I said, "Five years in
prison, nine kids at home, and your
father-in-law let you rot in prison for
doing his dirty work." But that's
typical. I mean, that there is nothing
unusual about that story. That was
typical.
>> So, amidst all this darkness, and I kind
of feel like I'm getting secondary drama
just from listening to this.
>> I know, right?
>> I can't imagine what what you
experienced.
>> Where did your values come from after
all this? He said you you don't regret
it. Where did your values come from for
this?
>> Oh, my parents and my grandparents. My
parents and my father's parents. Yeah.
We were a very strong nuclear family. I
come from a family of immigrants. All
four of my grandparents came from the
island of roads and were so incredibly
grateful to the United States for giving
them, you know, an opportunity to
thrive. When my grandparents left
Greece, there were no jobs. There wasn't
enough housing. There wasn't enough food
to feed everybody. And so the government
was actively encouraging young people to
just leave. Go to the US, Canada, the
UK, Australia, just just leave. And so
they left in 1931 on my dad's side, 1934
on my mom's side. My grandparents, my
dad's father especially, was such a deep
believer in the American dream, the
American experiment, that he instilled
in us this notion that we have to give
back, right? We have to pay the country
back for what it did for us. And so I
only considered public service. It never
even crossed my mind to go into the
private sector. And then at the same
time they sort of instilled in us this
notion that life is complicated but even
with life's complications
deep down we all know the difference
between right and wrong. All of us do
right it may be a difficult decision to
take to do the right thing but we know
what's right. And so without being you
know Mr. Goody two shoes I always tried
to do the right thing. Well, when it
came to the torture program, I felt so
strongly about it, like it was so
clearly wrong. I thought, you know, if
you look back through history where I
especially if you look back just at the
CIA where the CIA took actions or
implemented operations
that were clearly wrong, that always
ends up being revealed to the public.
The truth always comes out. Always.
Sometimes it takes years, decades, but
the truth always comes out. And I
thought, I've got to be on the right
side of this because I was involved,
right? I was one of those people there
at the creation of the torture program.
And you know, I thought, well,
historians are going to look at this
someday and they're going to say, "This
Kiryaku guy, why didn't he ever say
anything? Why didn't he ever try to stop
it?" And I thought, now they're wrong
and I'm right and I'm going for it. And
so that's what I did. But it was really
because of the strength that my parents
and grandparents gave me that allowed me
to do it.
>> How much of an impact does I presume
you're Orthodox? How much of an impact
does that have?
>> Yes, very very much. Very much. I take
my faith seriously. I even keep a
picture of a 20th century saint, St.
Necarios of Aena. I keep in my wallet so
that he's close to me.
>> Nice.
>> I've sort of adopted him as my as my
patron saint for a couple of reasons.
When I was first assigned to to Athens
as the counterterrorism officer, I was
doing a joint operation with the Greek
National Intelligence Service and we
went out to the island of Auna many
hours before we really needed to. But we
were afraid, oh, there's going to be,
you know, choppy waves and we're not
going to be able to get on the boat. And
we had to do this operation. So, we go
out like 6 hours early. And of course,
the sea was like oil. So, we just, you
know, skimmed right across the the water
to the island. And one of the Greek the
senior Greek officers said to me, "Have
you ever been to the home of St.
Nectarios?" And I said, "No, I would
love to see the home of St. Nectarios."
So, we went to the monastery and the
home and there's a little chapel. His
body is there and his bishop's crown and
all his possessions, his family photos,
his clothes. So, we went and this senior
Greek officer told the mother superior,
it's not a monastery, it's a convent. He
told the mother superior, "We're from
the Greek intelligence service and we
have an American Greek Orthodox and he
would like to see the saints home." They
let me sit on his bed. They let me sit
at his desk. It was just so cool. And
one of the reasons why I was so
attracted to his story was he had been a
young priest and he became a young
bishop in Cairo or in Alexandria rather
within the the patriarchet of
Alexandria. But because he was so young
and moving up so quickly, jealous
priests started a rumor that he was
having sex with female parishioners was
totally untrue. And he was stripped of
his bishop Rick and he was expelled from
Egypt and sent back to Greece. He was
penniless. Back then priests didn't work
for the government. There were no
pensions. You know, whatever donations
you got in the tray on Sunday, that's
what you lived on. So he even went
hungry and over the next 50 years built
this convent and a church and you know
etc etc. All those 50 years he prayed
for God to forgive the people who had
lied about him. He never accused them.
He never felt sorry for himself. It was
all about forgiveness. And I thought,
man, over 50 years. All he did was want
to forgive these people. They ruined his
life. He would have been the patriarch.
And he forgave them. And I thought, if
he can forgive them, then I certainly
can forgive the people who wronged me.
And then at the same time, people are
sending me biographies. I never read so
much in my life as I read in prison.
There's nothing else to do. So, you
know, I'm reading a biography of Nelson
Mandela, a biography of Martin Luther
King. Martin Luther King's last personal
assistant used to write me letters. We
corresponded back and forth. He's passed
away now. He sent me not just a
biography of King, but he sent me a
biography of King that he had written.
And so, I thought, "Wow, these people
suffered so much more than I did. I can
certainly just consider what happened to
me. Water under the bridge." So that's
what I did.
>> Okay. Well, I got to ask, maybe ending
it on a lighter note. What was it like
being on Tucker?
>> Oh, you know, he's the sweetest guy.
He's really a genuinely
sweet, kind, and downto-earth guy. When
he was at Fox, I was on his show maybe a
dozen times, and one of the things that
I really liked about his show was that
it was a longer form. I go on the Jesse
Waters show a lot now and I'm on for
literally 15 seconds literally. Like
that's the longest I've been on. 15
seconds with Tucker. I go on 15 minutes,
20 minutes and we sit there and talk and
then we go to commercial. We talk during
the commercial and we became friends.
And so he gave me his cell number. I
gave him my cell number. We would call
and chat or text. And he's just a
totally downto- earthth
sweet guy.
He mentioned one time he said, "You and
I probably disagree on 95% of the
issues." And I said, "We may. We may,
but I think we probably don't. I think
we're probably closer on issues than you
realize. Not because I'm farther to the
right than I acknowledge." I said,
"You're farther to the left than you
acknowledge."
And so, we remain friends all this time.
and he's actively helped me try to get a
pardon over the course of three
administrations now. Trump, Biden,
Trump. And um and he called me and said,
"Hey, why don't you come up?" He he he's
moved he sold his house in Washington.
He moved to Maine. And he said, "Why
don't you come up to Maine? We'll spend
a couple days and we'll do like a a
really long form interview." And so I
did. And he was absolutely wonderful.
Just a wonderful guy. I'm proud to call
him a friend. And you know, in
Washington, there's a famous uh saying
from Harry Truman, if you want a friend
in Washington, buy a dog, right? But but
Tucker's different. He's a genuine guy.
>> Amazing. Hope I have the privilege of
meeting him one day.
>> You'll like him a lot.
>> Well, th this was this was amazing,
John. Thank you for your witness to the
truth.
>> Thank you. Thank you for for having me.
I'm very happy to have been able to tell
these stories. Thanks for that.
>> I'm praying for your pardon.
>> Thank you. Me, too. Fingers crossed.
There's got to be somebody out there
that could whisper into Donald Trump's
ear. There's got to be. We'll see.
>> Yeah.
All right, Matt.
>> Yeah. Thank you. Take care of yourself.
>> Welcome. Take care.
>> Thanks for listening. Please like,
subscribe, and share with your friends.
See you next time.